Hallelujah!
Good morning, church!
You may be seated, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
With God, all things are possible.
Viewers all over the world and those who are under the influence of my voice,
whatever medium you are using to watch us,
we are with you and you are with us by faith.
Happy New Year! - let me greet you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This New Year, we shall talk about how we can equip ourselves and prepare for whatever challenges.
It's your year, no doubt about that.
It will come with strange and uncommon challenges but notwithstanding, it's your year!
If you go by the Year of Reward, God is your Rewarder; He's mine.
If God is your Rewarder, it's your year.
Say, "No matter the challenges, it's my year. God is my Rewarder."
Hallelujah.
Open with me the book of Matthew 5.
I will take my reading from verse 1, that is Matthew 5.
"Now when Jesus saw the crowds, he went up on a mountainside and sat down. His disciples came to him,
and he began to teach them."
He began to teach them what?
Let's go to the proof text.
Matthew 5:44, " But I tell you, love your enemies..."
I say hmm, because it has been an issue.
It's not that you don’t love – you love
but the kind of love you have is a love with expectation.
You have been loving and kind but love with what?
Expectation.
Jesus tells His disciples, "... love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you..."
You know what it means to love those who persecute you.
"… that you may be children of your Father in heaven.
He causes his sun to rise on the evil and the good,
and sends rain on the righteous and the unrighteous."
That means that both the evil and good enjoy the rain.
"If you love those who love you, what reward will you get?
Are not even the tax collectors doing that?"
The tax collectors do the same.
"And if you greet only your own people, what are you doing more than others?
Do not even pagans do that?
Be perfect, therefore, as your heavenly Father is perfect."
What the Bible is talking about is love without expectation.
Love without what?
Expectation.
When we love without expectation, our love is being sown to the Spirit.
To sow love to the Spirit is to honour God in our acts of love.
In whatever you do.
Anything you do to carry God along or honour Him,
you are doing it in Spirit because God is Spirit
and we worshippers worship Him in Spirit and truth.
I mean, in total humility and submission to His will.
I take you back again.
Because you are very very loving but with expectation.
You hardly love people without expectation.
You hardly give kiss to ugly person.
You prefer to give kiss to a beautiful and handsome person.
That is your expectation.
Your reward.
Are you there?
This is a New Year. I want to you to grow.
Use that opportunity of that reward that is coming for you because God is our Rewarder.
Love without expectation earns us the love of our Heavenly Father.
That is what the Bible is saying in Matthew 5:44.
"Love your enemies. Bless those who curse you."
Do good to those who hate you.
You will receive blessing of your Heavenly Father.
You know, I said that you are very loving and so kind but with expectation.
Hardly will you do something without expecting something.
It's all about selfish, classic and material reasons.
Love without expectation earns us the love of our Heavenly Father.
"Our Father who art in Heaven, hallowed be Thy name; Thy Kingdom come."
When you sow God's love, you reap God's love.
We need to develop faith in this spiritual law.
We need to develop faith in what?
Spiritual what?
Spiritual law.
You just have to develop faith.
If your faith is in your faith, you are deceiving yourself.
That is "tit for tat".
If your faith is faith in faith, faith in yourself, it is "tit for tat".
Hit me, I hit you.
But faith in the finished work of our Lord, Jesus Christ,
must be developed in this spiritual law.
Love without expectation says, 'Love your enemies,
bless those who curse you, do good to those who hate you
and you will receive the blessing of your Heavenly Father'.
That is it.
This year, for you to receive that reward, great reward, you must love without expectation.
Expectation of certain behaviours from loved ones, relatives, acquaintances
and friends sets us up for offence.
Take for instance, I expect you to greet me because of help I rendered
or my superiority in age or my position as pastor T.B. Joshua - you are a member of the church
I'm expecting you to greet me, and you ignore me.
This is a major root of offence.
T.B. Joshua is expecting you to greet him.
You are a member of the church, and I am going,
but you just walk away from me, ignoring me.
This is a major root of offence.
It is because I expect you to greet me, because of my position, my superiority of age, or whatever.
We often get disappointed and offended when our expectations are not met.
Cut down on your expectation from people
before you set up yourself for offence.
Tell your neighbour, "Cut down on your expectation from people before you set up yourself for offence".
Viewers all over the world, listen to me.
Cut down on your expectation from people before you set up yourself for offence.
Expectations of certain behaviours should carefully be observed.
Tell your neighbour, "Expectations of certain behaviours should carefully be observed".
I expect Mr A to do this and Mr B to do that.
There is nothing bad with that but that should not lead to offence.
We are often shocked, surprised and confused when offended,
as if we are the only ones wronged, as if no one else has ever been wronged.
Yet, Jesus made it clear in Luke 17:1 – it is impossible to live this life
and not have the opportunity to be offended.
In Luke 17:1, He said it is impossible to live this life and not have the opportunity to be offended.
I mean, it is impossible that no offences should come.
It is not a question of opportunity to be offended but what your response will be.
Tell your neighbour, "My response determines my future".
When I'm hurt, deeply hurt, bitter, my response determines my future.
Take note of that.
If you know that tactic and strategy of satan, you overcome satan.
When I'm hurt, deeply hurt, bitter, cheated, wrongly accused, my response determines my future.
Stand up and tell the viewers all over the world.
Stretch your hand and tell them, so that the awareness will grow.
Viewers, when you are hurt, deeply hurt, bitter, wrongly accused, persecuted,
your response determines your future.
You may be seated.
Now, from this moment, when somebody tries you mistreat you, or accuse you wrongly -
"why pushing me?" - be careful.
Two wrongs do not make a right.
Or when you moved just a little from your place, and somebody took over your seat,
you come back to your seat, even your Bible which was there was moved by this person
who sat on your seat.
Be careful. Your response determines your future.
When you expect someone to pay your money, and you move with police, security and you want to...
Or your landlord.
A landlord today can be a tenant tomorrow and a tenant today can be a landlord tomorrow.
A pastor today can be a drunkard tomorrow and a drunkard today can be a pastor tomorrow.
You rich man – a rich man today can be a poor man tomorrow
and a poor man today can be a rich man tomorrow.
A sinner today can be a righteous man tomorrow
and a righteous man today can be a sinner tomorrow.
This is why the Bible says the beginner is not the owner but the finisher.
There is a race.
There is a race that I must run
There are victories to be won
Give me power every hour to be true
There is a race
There is a race that I must run
There are victories to be won
Give me power every hour to be true
There is a race
There is a race that I must run
There are victories to be won
Give me power every hour to be true
Oh Lord see me through
See me through
Lord Jesus see me through
There is a race
There is a race that I must run
There are victories to be won
Give me power every hour to be true
The Lord will see you through!
You may be seated.
Viewers all over the world, those of you under the influence of my voice,
the Lord will see you through.
Amen.
The book of Galatians says that if one is caught in act of wrong,
you that caught the person should restore the person gently, so that you will not be tempted.
Your response when you are hurt, embarrassed, mistreated, misjudged,
wrongly accused, persecuted, hated, your response determines your future.
Jesus on the Cross, said, "Father, forgive them".
'Them' means offender and offended. "Father, forgive them".
Often, the response we exhibit leaves us vulnerable to a root of bitterness.
Take note of that.
Often, the response we exhibit leaves us vulnerable to a root of bitterness,
anger, strife, outrage, jealousy, envy, hatred and resentment.
We must therefore be ready, prepared and strongly armed for offence
because our response determines our future.
When you get home, open the Book of Acts 24:16.
You must therefore be ready, prepared and strongly armed for offence.
You wake up in the morning and you expect your little baby to greet you,
but it ignores you.
"What is wrong with you?"
From "what is wrong with you?" to anger, from anger bitterness, from bitterness the jealousy, and so on...
You are trapped, in prison.
Offence is the effective instrument used by satan.
Offence is very common, epidemic, rampant, unavoidable,
occurs everywhere, bound to happen because the Bible says, it is impossible
to live among people and not have the opportunity to be offended.
It is bound to happen everywhere.
We have almost come to believe that it is a way of life
because it is common everywhere.
If satan wants to imprison you, he knows how to go about it – through offence.
Satan wants to embarrass you through offence.
Look at what happened to Job.
Satan came to God - this man You say is righteous, let me tempt him, let me provoke him, let me hurt him
let me cause bitterness in him.
Viewers, listen to me.
All your dreams for many years will come through this year.
Viewers, whatever medium you are using to watch us,
once you are under the influence of my voice,
your dreams for many years – come through this year!
Dream of finances, breakthrough, good health, prosperity – come through!
In the name of Jesus!
Viewers, I separate you from nightmares!
Be separated, in the name of Jesus!
When I say, 'nightmare', I mean every foolish thing.
Just think of any foolish thing – the root of satan, the root of offence.
Viewers, listen once again: By the authority in the name of Jesus,
whatever medium you are using to watch us,
so far as you are under the influence of my voice,
(come on)
I separate you from nightmares!
Be separated!
Jesus loves you. Your response determines your future.
Offence – there's nothing you can do about it.
The only thing – don’t feed on it in your heart; don’t act it.
People will offend you. Offence itself is not deadly.
As it stays in your heart, it is not deadly.
Well, it is not the easiest road to take – humility and self-denial,
like I have said.
When people embarrass you, curse you, misjudge you, persecute you,
lie against you, wrong accusation – your response is your weapon.
It's the key to loose or bind.
It's either that response locks you more or opens the future.
When satan knows you are doing well and happy, he comes with offence.
Your reaction to that offence determines your future.
Tell your neighbour, "Your reaction to that offence determines your future".
When they know you are happy, your family and you are good, everything is alright...
When you plan to go to the church in your "posh car" and the engine knocks - you say,
"oh no, I cannot go to the church" - it means that satan has trapped you.
You say to your family, "my family, we cannot go the church because the engine knocked".
Who gave you the vehicle?
Is it a crime to bless you?
When you didn't have the vehicle, you knew how to come to the church, how to worship your God.
Now a blessing of God became what?
A burden.
A crime.
I was telling my people last week that we must not take an offence.
When you are fasting, praying, you are happy with yourself, a mosquito will just come from nowhere,
and makes sure it feeds on you, and becomes full of blood.
When you just hit you see a lot of blood on your beautiful garment.
Would you not hold offence?
"What is all this?"
From offence comes what?
Anger, outrage, strifes.
This New Year, you should carefully observe the major root of what?
Offence.
God bless you. Rise up.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I will not leave you without offering this prayer; it’s a prophetic word.
Join me in prayer.
For so long you have been dreaming but your dream has not come through.
This is the year!
Open your lips, right now.
Your dreams for many years – come through this year!
Come through this year.
Dream of finances, prosperity, good health -
come through, in the name of Jesus!
Begin to separate yourself from your situation.
Separate yourself from that nightmare!
Separate yourself.
I separate myself from that nightmare!
Be separated!
Viewers all over the world, be separated!
Begin to separate yourself from that sickness!
Separate yourself from that setback!
Separate yourself!
Separate yourself from that fleshly desire and thought!
Fleshly desire and thought!
Separate yourself!
In the name of Jesus Christ!
Tell your neighbour, “when I’m hurt, deeply hurt, bitter, my response determines my future”.
Offence is the effective instrument used by satan to trap you,
to imprison you and to make you a bond-servant.
That is - he can send you an errand to kill to destroy and to make you a bond-servant.
Are you with me?
Listen, say to yourself,
“Offence is the effective instrument used by satan to trap you,
to imprison you – I mean to make you a bond-servant”.
Yes.
Your reaction to that offence gives birth to hurt, anger, jealousy, envy, outrage, strifes,
resentment – just name it.
Therefore, your response determines your future.
Whether you are wrong or right, you do not have permission or the right
to hold onto offence because two wrongs do not make a right.
Tell your neighbour, “whether you are right or wrong, wrongly accused or not,
persecuted or not, you do not have the right or permission to hold onto offence
because two wrongs do not make a right”.
Tell your neighbour once again.
Because you are persecuted, mistreated, wrongly accused, falsely accused or cheated,
you do not have a right or permission to hold onto offence because two wrongs do not make a right.
This is what Jesus meant,
“Bless those who curse you and do good to those who hate you”.
Tell your neighbour – this is what Jesus meant -
Until you begin to live and love without expectation, your life will continue to be epileptic.
Today good, tomorrow...
Up and down, business is going well, tomorrow no...
Until you continue to love without expectation...
Tell your neighbour, "Love without expectation".
I cannot hear you.
Love without expectation.
Care without expectation.
I cannot hear you.
Again.
Care without expectation.
Love without expectation.
I cannot hear you.
Care without expectation.
Again and again.
Love without expectation.
Care without expectation.
Whether is comes or not, I am not expecting it.
If I care for you, I am not expecting a reward because my reward is from Heaven.
You are not even the person that will reward me.
If I care for you, someone is somewhere to reward me.
Hallelujah!
YOU CANNOT WATCH THIS MESSAGE AND REMAIN THE SAME!!!
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today,
and stay up to date for the latest prophecies, deliverances, service and testimonies from the SCOAN.
Emmanuel TV - changing lives, changing nations and changing the world.
RV Robert Begier 21/04/2019